import { images } from './index.js';
const { exp_1, exp_3, exp_5, exp_7, exp_8, exp_9, exp_10, exp_11, exp_12, exp_13, exp_14, exp_15, exp_16, exp_17, exp_18, exp_19, exp_20, exp_21, mexp_21, exp_22, 
  exp_23, exp_24, exp_25, exp_26,exp_27, exp_28, exp_29, exp_30, exp_31, exp_32, exp_33, exp_34, exp_35, exp_36, exp_37, exp_38, exp_39, exp_40 } = images;



export default Maths_Model_2015  = [
    {
      id: "h1",
      Number_of_Questions: "40 Questions",
      Time_Allowed: "1 hour",
      title: "Maths Model 2015"
    },
    // {
    //   id: 'h2',
    //   header1: " KOLFE KERANIO SUB CITY EDUCATION BUREAU GRADE 8 MATHEMATICS MODEL EXAMINATIONS 2016E.C/ 2024G.C"
    // },
      {
      id: 1,
      question: "Which one of the following number is both perfect square and perfect Cube number?",
      options: ["625", "0.09", "1/64", "1600"],
      correct_option: "625",
      explanation_Image: exp_1,
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        maths_question: ` is a rational number, a < b and b$\\neq 0$  then it is ______`,
        options: ["Improper fraction", "Proper fraction", "mixed fraction", "Opposite number"],
        correct_option: "Proper fraction",
        explanation: 'The correct answer is "Proper fraction." In mathematics, a proper fraction is a fraction where the numerator is less than the denominator. Since a < b and b ≠ 0 in the given scenario, it fits the definition of a proper fraction.'
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: "Which one of the following number is perfect cube number?",
        options: ["0.08", "0.027", "0.64", "0.81"],
        correct_option: "0.027",
        explanation_Image: exp_3,
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: "Which one of the following rational number is the greatest?",
        options: ["-100", "-89", "-10", "0"],
        correct_option: "0",
        explanation: 'Rational numbers can be positive, negative, or zero. When comparing negative rational numbers, the number that is closer to zero is greater because it has a higher value. For example, -10 is greater than -100 because it is closer to zero on the number line.\n' +
              "Here’s a simple comparison: \n" +
              "-100 is less than -89 \n" +
              "-89 is less than -10 \n" +
              "-10 is less than 0 \n" +
              "Therefore, out of the given options, 0 is the greatest because it is the highest value on the number line among the listed numbers."
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        maths_question: "When x$\\epsilon$  Q , which one of the following is the solution for $\\frac{x+4}{7} + \\frac{x+9}{14}=10$",
        options: ["123/3", "123", "125", "13/19"],
        correct_option: "123/3",
        explanation_Image: exp_5,
      },
      {
        id: 6,
        question: "Which one of the following is true?",
        maths_options: ["$\\frac{1}{2}$ < $\\frac{3}{5}$ < $\\frac{7}{10}$", 
        "$\\frac{7}{10}$ < $\\frac{3}{5}$ < $\\frac{1}{2}$",
         "$\\frac{1}{2}$ < $\\frac{7}{10}$ < $\\frac{3}{5}$", 
         "$\\frac{3}{5}$ < $\\frac{7}{10}$ < $\\frac{1}{2}$"],
        correct_option: "$\\frac{1}{2}$ < $\\frac{3}{5}$ < $\\frac{7}{10}$",
        
      },
      {
        id: 7,
        question: "Which one of the following number is odd perfect cube?",
        options: ["216", "512", "729", "1000"],
        correct_option: "729",
        explanation_Image: exp_7,
      },
      {
        id: 8,
        maths_question: "If $(128)^{2}$ = B  then find $(0.892)^{2}$",
        options: ["B/1000", "B/100", "B/10", "B/25"],
        correct_option: "B/1000",
        explanation_Image: exp_8,
      },
      {
        id: 9,
        maths_question: " The area of square $1225m^{2}$ then find the length of the side of square",
        options: ["35m", "25m", "5m", "95m"],
        correct_option: "35m",
        explanation_Image: exp_9,
      },
      {
        id: 10,
        maths_question: "If $(8.57)^{2}$ = 73.44 then what is $\\sqrt{7344}$",
        options: ["857", "764.4", "85.7", "734.4"],
        correct_option: "85.7",
        explanation_Image: exp_10,
      },
      {
        id: 11,
        question: "Five times a certain number is decreased by two times the number is less" + 
        "than 12. What are the possible values of this number in the domain of W?",
        options: ["{ 0,1,2,3 }", "{ 4,5,6 }", "{ 1,2,3 }", "{ -1,-2,-3 }"],
        correct_option: "{ 0,1,2,3 }",
        explanation_Image: exp_11,
      },
      {
        id: 12,
        maths_question: "If the volume of cube is $\\frac{1}{8}m^{3}$.then find the length of cube.",
        maths_options: ["$\\frac{1}{2}$m", "$\\frac{2}{3}$m", "64m", "4m"],
        correct_option: "$\\frac{1}{2}$m",
        explanation_Image: exp_12,
      },
      {
        id: 13,
        maths_question: "$\\sqrt{5x+6} = 6$ then what is the value of x?",
        options: ["6", "4", "3", "36"],
        correct_option: "6",
        explanation_Image: exp_13,
      },
      {
        id: 14,
        maths_question: "Let x = 6 and y= -8 the then the simplified form of $(\\sqrt[3]{x^{2}+y^{2}})$ is",
        options: ["100", "300", "30", "3915"],
        correct_option: "30",
        explanation_Image: exp_14,
      },
      {
        id: 15,
        question: "The graph of y= -10x is pass through,",
        maths_options: ["below the x- axis", "$1^{st}$ and $3^{nd}$ quadrants", " above the x-axis", "$2^{nd}$ and $4^{th}$ quadrants"],
        correct_option: "$2^{nd}$ and $4^{th}$ quadrants",
        explanation_Image: exp_15,
      },
      {
        id: 16,
        maths_question: "The descending order of $2\\frac{1}{3},\\frac{1}{5},\\frac{3}{4}$",
        maths_options: ["$2\\frac{1}{3},\\frac{3}{4},0.5,\\frac{1}{5}$", "$\\frac{3}{4},2\\frac{1}{3},\\frac{1}{5},0.5$", 
        "$\\frac{1}{5},0.5,\\frac{3}{4},2\\frac{1}{3}$", "$0.5,\\frac{1}{5},2\\frac{1}{3},\\frac{3}{4}$"],
        correct_option: "$2\\frac{1}{3},\\frac{3}{4},0.5,\\frac{1}{5}$",
        explanation_Image: exp_16,
      },
      {
        id: 17,
        maths_question: "$(\\frac{3}{4})$ 3 = _____________",
        maths_options: ["9/16", "27/64", "27/16", "9/64"],
        correct_option: "27/64",
        explanation_Image: exp_17,
      },
      {
        id:18,
        question: "-2|3x-1|= -8, then  what is the value of x?",
        maths_options: ["{ 1, $\\frac{3}{5}$ }", "{ -1, $\\frac{5}{3}$ }", 
        "{ -1, -$\\frac{5}{3}$ }", "{ -1, -5 }"],
        correct_option: "{ -1, $\\frac{5}{3}$ }",
        explanation_Image: exp_18,
      },
      {
        id:19,
        maths_question: "The product of -$\\frac{2}{3} X \\frac{5}{4} X \\frac{3}{2}$",
        maths_options: ["-$\\frac{5}{4}$", "-$\\frac{3}{4}$", "1",
        "$\\frac{5}{4}$"],
        correct_option: "-$\\frac{5}{4}$",
        explanation_Image: exp_19,
      },
      {
        id:20,
        question: "3/4 + 1/3 = ______________",
        options: ["13/12", "4/11", "8/39","7/6"],
        correct_option: "13/12",
        explanation_Image: exp_20,
      },
      {
        id:21,
        question: "How long will take birr 4000 to get birr 800 simple interest at rate of 20%? ",
        options: ["1 year", "2 year", "3 year","5 year"],
        correct_option: "1 year",
        explanation_Image: mexp_21,
      },
      {
        id:22,
        question: "Positive proper fraction always exist between _____",
        options: ["0 and 1", "-1 and 0", "1 and 2","-2 and -1"],
        correct_option: "0 and 1",
        explanation_Image: exp_21,
      },
      {
        id:23,
        question: "Determine the quotient of 4/6 by 2/6",
        options: ["6", "3/2", "6/7","2"],
        correct_option: "2",
        explanation_Image: exp_23,
      },
      {
        id:24,
        maths_question: "Which one of the following is true about? $\\sqrt[3]{Y} = Z$ ?",
        maths_options: ["Y is the cube root of Y", "Z is the cube root of Y.", "$Z=Y^{3}$","$Y=Z^{\\frac{1}{3}}$"],
        correct_option: "Z is the cube root of Y.",
        explanation_Image: exp_24,
      },
      {
        id:25,
        question: "Which one of the following is true about the prime factorization of 225?",
        maths_options: ["$3^2$ x 5", "3 X $5^2$", "$3^3$ x 5","$3^3$ x $3^2 x 5^2"],
        correct_option: "$3^3$ x 5",
        explanation_Image: exp_25,
      },
      {
        id:26,
        question: "If birr 2,000 is invested at a rate of 12 ℅ simple interest calculated annually" +
        "then what is the total amount after 4 years?",
        maths_options: ["960", "1960", "2960","3000"],
        correct_option: "2960",
        explanation_Image: exp_26,
      },
      {
        id:27,
        question: "Which one of the following rational number is mixed fraction?",
        maths_options: ["$6\\frac{4}{3}$", "$\\frac{6}{5}$", "$7\\frac{2}{3}$","$\\frac{11}{15}$"],
        correct_option: "$6\\frac{4}{3}$",
        explanation_Image: exp_27,
      },
      {
        id:28,
        question: "which quadrant does the coordinate point (-400,600)",
        maths_options: ["$4^{th}$  quadrant", "$3^{rd}$  quadrant", "$2^{nd}$  quadrant","$1^{st}$  quadrant"],
        correct_option: "$2^{nd}$  quadrant",
        explanation_Image: exp_28,
      },
      {
        id:29,
        question: "Which of the following statement is true?",
        maths_options: ["$(\\frac{a}{b})2 = \\frac{a}{b}$", "$(ab)^2 = (a)^2(b)^2$", "$a^2 = a + a$","$\\sqrt{\\frac{a}{b}} = \\frac{a}{b}$"],
        correct_option: "$(ab)^2 = (a)^2(b)^2$",
        explanation_Image: exp_29,
      },
      {
        id:30,
        question: "If Y is a perfect cube if and only if ",
        maths_options: ["$Y = m^3$", "$Y = n^2$", "$Y = \\sqrt{m}$","$Y = \\sqrt[3]{m}$ "],
        correct_option: "$Y = m^3$",
        explanation_Image: exp_30,
      },
      {
        id:31,
        question: "One of the following line passes through the origin",
        options: ["x = 3", "y = 4x", "y = 2x + 2","y = -6"],
        correct_option: "y = 4x",
        explanation_Image: exp_31,
      },
      {
        id:32,
        question: "The slope of Y= -3x+5 is",
        options: ["3", "-3", "4","-4"],
        correct_option: "-3",
        explanation_Image: exp_32,
      },
      {
        id:33,
        question: "Which one of the following equation is equivalent to -2 x+ 4 = 3?",
        options: ["x = 2", "-2x = 4", "2x = 4","-2x = -1"],
        correct_option: "-2x = -1",
        explanation_Image: exp_33,
      },
      {
        id:34,
        question: "Which one of the following show Associative property of Addition?",
        options: ["A + D = D + C", "C(A + B) = AC + BC", "C + (A + B) = A + (C + B)","A + 0 = A"],
        correct_option: "C + (A + B) = A + (C + B)",
        explanation_Image: exp_34,
      },
      {
        id:35,
        question: "Which one of the following statement is true?",
        options: ["The product of an odd number of negative rational numbers is positive", 
        "The product of opposite sign is positive", 
        "The product of an odd number of negative factors is negative.",
        "The product of both negative is negative."],
        correct_option: "The product of an odd number of negative factors is negative.",
        explanation_Image: exp_35,
      },
      {
        id:36,
        maths_question: "The value of  is $\\sqrt[3]{16/54}$",
        options: ["4/7", "8/27", "2/3","4/3"],
        correct_option: "2/3",
        explanation_Image: exp_36,
      },
      {
        id:37,
        question: "If x=1 and y=2,then What is the value of 4y(3x-y)+5(3x-y) ?",
        options: ["15", "9", "13","22"],
        correct_option: "13",
        explanation_Image: exp_37,
      },
      {
        id:38,
        question: "What is the solution set of the inequality 6(2+4x) ≤ 42 in the set of positive integers?",
        options: ["{ 0,1,2 }", "{ 1 }", "{ 1,2 }","{}"],
        correct_option: "{ 1 }",
        explanation_Image: exp_38,
      },
      {
        id:39,
        question: "What is the solution set of the equation 2(3x+5) = 30?",
        options: ["{ 10/3 }", "{ 4 }", "{ 1/2 }","{1/6}"],
        correct_option: "{ 10/3 }",
        explanation_Image: exp_39,
      },
      {
        id:40,
        question: "A father is 27 years older than his son. Ten years ago he was twice as old as his son. How old is the father now?",
        options: ["54 years", "37 years", "47 years","64 years"],
        correct_option: "64 years",
        explanation_Image: exp_40,
      },
  ]